<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on DATA 650 Blog - Ron Richardson</title>
    <link>/tags/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on DATA 650 Blog - Ron Richardson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing flexdashboard</title>
      <link>/post/introducing-flexdashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introducing-flexdashboard/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionDashboards are great tools for grouping common visualizations together into one page or site. This allows the user to consume large amounts of visualizations in a quick and easy method.
Example DashboardA search for dashboard on Google will result in millions of results. To show you a real life example, I have built a simple dashboard showing some basic statistics of my golf game over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggplot - Interactive Bar Plots</title>
      <link>/post/using-ggplot-interactive-bar-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-ggplot-interactive-bar-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionSometimes, just having a chart isn’t enough. When working on the web, interactivity is key to capturing a user’s interest and attention. One simple way of doing so, is by adding a tooltip or hover effect to the data points. Not only is this great for the user’s attention, it helps with the readability of the data as well.
Basic ExampleWe are introducing a new library called ggiraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggplot - Time Series</title>
      <link>/post/using-ggplot-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-ggplot-time-series/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA new chart to introduce is called a time series. This type is used when you want to visualize data along a period of time. The x-axis represents the time and the y-axis represents the data. This is a subset of the line graph, as a line graph doesn’t have a precondition of the x-axis representing time.
Basic ExampleFor this example we will use the number of home runs that Babe Ruth during his career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggplot - Bar Plots</title>
      <link>/post/using-ggplot-bar-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-ggplot-bar-plots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA bar plot uses rectangular bars (like a histogram) to represent data that is grouped into a series, sized accordingly based on the numerical value associated with it. The rectangular bars can be displayed either vertically or horizontally.
Basic ExampleFirst, we must gather our data. For this example, we will gather the number of home runs a team hit in 1980. For this purpose, we are ordering the results by the number of home runs hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggplot - Histograms</title>
      <link>/post/using-ggplot-histograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-ggplot-histograms/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA histogram uses rectangular bars to represent data that is grouped into a series, sized accordingly based on the numerical value associated with it. The rectangular bars can be displayed either vertically or horizontally.
Basic ExampleFirst, we must gather our data. Here we are using the Lahman database and obtaining all of the weights of baseball players throughout the years.
#import librarieslibrary(Lahman)library(dplyr)library(ggplot2)#store data into a variable named dfdf&amp;lt;-Master %&amp;gt;%filter(!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ggplot - Scatterplots</title>
      <link>/post/using-ggplot-scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/using-ggplot-scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionA scatterplot is a useful visualization that compares two series of numbers against each other. This can be great for determining a correlation between the series. In our example below, we will compare Babe Ruth’s career home runs against his career strikeouts to see if there is any relationship between how many home runs he hit and if that means more strike outs.
Basic ExampleFirst we need to import our libraries and gather our basic data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lahman database using dplyr</title>
      <link>/post/lahman-database-using-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lahman-database-using-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe Lahman database is a publically accessible database of baseball statistics. This database contains multiple tables of data from a large time series, which makes it great to run experiments against.
dplyr is an R package which allows programmatic access to this data using concepts very similar to T-SQL.
InitializationsOnce the packages are installed, they need to be loaded into the environemnt. This is accomplished with two lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>